Finding Aid for William K. Frankena Papers 1927-1991
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Lectures and Papers, 1930-1987; 1.7 linear feet
  - "Stevenson and the Emotive Theory of Ethics" (Washington, D.C. Philosophy Society), 1979 (Box 11)
  - "Tendencies in Contemporary Philosophy of Education,", undated (Box 11)
  - "Thinking about Morality" (LSA Distinguished Senior Faculty Lecture Series), 1978; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - "Thoughts After Hare's Visit,", 1985 (Box 11)
  - "Three Questions About Morality" (Paul Carus Lectures, American Philosophical Association), 1974; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - "Toward A Philosophy Of The Family" (University of Minnesota), 1969 (Box 11)
  - "Toward A Policy For Public Education" (National Academy of Education), undated (Box 11)
  - "Two Notes on Representation,", 1966 (Box 11)
  - "Values In The Humanities and Fine Arts" (Macalester College), 1964 (Box 11)
  - "Visions of Morality" (Calvin College), 1976 (Box 11)
  - Wheaton College Lectures, 1970 (Box 11)
  - "Wild On Causation And Responsibility,", 1962 (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, 1930-1970; 4 folders (Box 11)
- Topical, 1949-1980; 1.5 linear feet
  The Topical series (1.5 linear feet; 1949-1980) includes various materials collected by Frankena for projects, conferences, professional activities, and subjects on which he was planning to write; it has been arranged alphabetically.
  - Aiken, Henry D., "Contra 'The Moral Point of View'", circa 1980 (Box 11)
  - Being and Doing, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Bibliography of Frankena (Box 11)
  - Black Paper (Box 11)
  - Bollnow, Virtue, Etc (Box 11)
  - Book Reviews (Box 11)
  - Brandt Notes (Box 11)
  - British Ethics Notes (sample), 1960-1970 (Box 11)
  - Broad, C.D. (Box 12)
  - Broad Lectures, 1952 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Summer Institute in Philosophy, 1972 (Box 12)
  - Conference Programs, 1971 (Box 12)
  - Council For Philosophical Studies (Box 12)
  - Democracy (Box 12)
  - Dissertation Approval, 1977-1980 (Box 12)
  - Editing Work (Box 12)
  - Ethics, 1949-1953 (Box 12)
  - Family (Box 12)
  - Founding Of The National Academy Of Education (Box 12)
  - Guggenheim Fellow (Box 12)
  - Hall's "What Is Value?" (Box 12)
  - Hampshire, Stuart (Box 12)
  - Human Rights, 1952 (Box 12)
  - Hume (Box 12)
  - In The News (Box 12)
  - "Justice As Fairness" (Box 12)
  - Kant (Box 12)
  - Language Papers (Box 12)
  - Moore, G.E (Box 12)
  - Moral Education (Box 12)
  - Morality (Box 12)
  - Motivation and Obligation (Box 12)
  - Old and New Morality (Box 12)
  - "On 'The Upside-down Curriculum" (Box 12)
  - Parker, DeWitt (Box 12)
  - Plato and Poetry (Box 12)
  - Plato vs Aristotle (Box 12)
  - Relevance In Education (Box 12)
  - Rights (Box 12)
  - Sidgwick (Box 13)
  - Sincerity and Authenticity (Box 13)
  - Social Justice Book Essay and Princeton Project (Box 13)
  - Social Justice (Box 13)
  - Social Morality, Institutions, Etc (Box 13)
  - Socrates and Simonides (Box 13)
  - Spinoza (Box 13)
  - Stameshkin (Box 13)
  - Stevenson, Charlie Leslie (Box 13)
  - Virtue (Box 13)
  - Vocabulary (Box 13)
  - Vocational Education (Box 13)
- Correspondence, 1934-1991; 1.7 linear feet
  The Correspondence series (1.7 linear feet; 1934-1991) includes correspondence produced by Frankena throughout his career. It is arranged chronologically for about half of the series and by the name of the corresponding person or organization for the remainder.
  - Chronological
    - 1934, 1939; 1941; 1943-1953 (Box 13)
    - 1954-1970, 14 folders (Box 13)
    - 1971-1972, 1977-1978 (Box 13)
    - 1975 (Box 13)
    - 1981 (Box 13)
    - Fragmentary (Box 13)
    - Undated (Box 13)
  - Alphabetical
    - Aiken, Henry D (Box 14)
    - American Philosophical Association And Its Committees (Box 14)
    - Arner, Douglas (Box 14)
    - Brandt, Richard (Box 14)
    - Broad, C.D (Box 14)
    - Center For Advanced Study In The Behavioral Sciences (Box 14)
    - Chatham College (Box 14)
    - Conference In Philosophy Of Education (Box 14)
    - Cornell University (Box 14)
    - Harper & Brothers (Box 14)
    - Harvard University (Box 14)
    - Henle, Paul (Box 14)
    - Kiefer, Howard E. (State University College at Brockport) (Box 14)
    - Leonard, Henry S (Box 14)
    - Lepley, Ray (Box 14)
    - Letters of Recommendation, 1951-1991; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Lewis, C.I (Box 14)
    - Macmillan Company (Box 14)
    - Maurice Mandelbaum (Maurie) (Box 14)
    - Melden, A.I. (Abe) (Box 14)
    - Morgan, Douglas (Box 14)
    - National Foundation On The Arts And The Humanities (Box 14)
    - Notre Dame (Box 14)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton III (Box 14)
    - Reiner, Hans (Box 14)
    - The Review of Metaphysics (Box 14)
    - Rockfeller Foundation (Box 14)
    - Russell, Bruce, 1983 (Box 14)
    - Scheffler, Israel (Harvard) (Box 14)
    - Stevenson, Charles and Nora (Box 14)
    - University Center in Virginia (Box 14)
    - Visiting Committees (Box 14)
    - Vlastos, Gregory (Box 14)
    - Yale University (Box 14)
- University of Michigan Activities, 1945-1963; 0.3 linear feet
  The final series documents Frankena's University of Michigan Activities (.3 linear feet; 1945-1963). This includes material from committees on which he served, functions as chairman of the Philosophy Department, and speeches at the University of Michigan. It is arranged alphabetically.
  - Committees
    - College Problems, 1945 (Box 14)
    - Deanship, 1950 (Box 14)
    - Qualifications, 1960-1963 (Box 14)
    - Religion, 1948 (Box 14)
    - Reports, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Department of Philosophy (Box 14)
  - Promotion Recommendations, 1959-1961 (Box 14)
  - Speeches (Box 14)